CV english.md 8/1/2018

Independent developer and software architect

Kristian Videmark Parkov

Born August 9, 1980 Tranevej 15, 2. th. 2400 Copenhagen NV, Denmark hej@bitkompagniet.dk LinkedIn Bitkompagniet ApS



Full-stack / backend developer with focus on software architecture and with leader experience. Started my career with focus on web, and have since moved towards more complicated software systems within public administration, research and finance. I have clear strengths on the backend side of development, but I still have a lot of experience implementing a web interface in the form of a REST API and a React frontend.

In 2013 I started my own company (Bitkompagniet - Danish only), and have done a number of projects both as a supplier and an on-site consultant. My role has varied greatly - some projects I have done alone, in others I have been a team member or technical lead.

I am focused on process and project models, and I am a fan of test driven development, code reviews and a reasonable git flow.

I live in Copenhagen with my girlfriend Ida and our daughter Liva.

Keywords

Software architecture, C#, .NET, Javascript / Node.js, React, PHP, SQL, MongoDB, REST API, integrations, Git, Docker, Test Driven Development (TDD), managerial experience, communication, Scrum

Experience

Founder and developer, Bitkompagniet ApS

2013 - nu

Offers project- and consultantbased services in software development, web and databases, often with integration to other systems.

Examples:

- Core modules for molecular and protein modelling for Novo Nordisk A/S. C# / .NET Core / class library
- Application for finding the best supplier for a given basket of items in a public framework agreement for Moderniseringsstyrelsen. C# / .NET / MVC
- Self service system for student loans on borger.dk. C# / .NET / MVC

See the full list of projects.

CV_english.md 8/1/2018

Lead developer, MOC A/S

2011 - 2013

Team lead on a four man development team. Development of web applications and websites in TYPO3 CMS.

- Software architecture
- Quality assurance of team output
- Development in PHP, javascript, HTML/CSS, MySQL
- Module development and website implementation
- On-site consultant for a time

Projects include:

- DMI (Danish Meteorological Institute) website re-implementation.
- VUC websites for 11 institutions into a common platform.
- Consultant at TopDanmark, working on re-implementation of corporate website.

Academic Officer, IT University of Copenhagen

2009 - 2011

Strategic role with focus on student well-being and progress.

- Analysis of student status and strategies for progress.
- Responsiblity for the introduction activities for new students.
- Recurring managerial duties for the eight student counselors.

Education

MSc.IT., Media Technology & games, IT University of Copenhagen

2006 - 2009

Selected activities:

- Thesis about rehabilitation tools for aphasia patients inspired by games. Grade: 12
- Cooperation with DR (Danish Broadcasting Corporation) about creating news-related Flash games for their official website.
- Courses in artificial intelligence, development in 3D engines (Unity) and gamification.
- Two student jobs as a study advisor on the university, and a developer at a pension fund.

BA.Soc., Communication & Computer Science, Roskilde University

2002 - 2005

Udvalgte aktiviteter:

- Bachelors in virtual spaces as cooperation platform (CSCW).
- Courses in programming (Java), SQL-databases (SQL), Domain Driven Design and much more.
- Basic education in social studies with focus on quantitative analysis and economics.

CV_english.md 8/1/2018

Projects

Core libraries for protein modelling, Novo Nordisk A/S

Software architect / developer / on-site consultant

Aug 2017 - Jun 2018

Re-implementation of existing core libraries in a more modern programming language, with a number of specification adjustments. Core libraries for runtime modelling of molecules and protein structures, with analysis and optimization. Worked solo on the core library, after which the implementation and the project was brought into a broader scope in a number of dependent projects. I continued as a project member until the end of all the projects.

Integration for internal web services (SOAP).

C#, .NET Core, XUnit

Website build tool, Svift

Software architect in an advisory capacity

Jun 2016 - Aug 2017

Tool to make websites with no techincal skills, offered for personal use and small businesses. Great frontend challenges with requirements for editing templates and stylesheets in the browser.

Integrations for Kubernetes and Stripe.

Microservices, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, ES6, React, Redux, Docker, Git

Symbiosis database, Dansk SymbioseCenter

Software architect / developer

Jan 2017 - Jun 2017

Production companies produce waste, which might be resources for some other companies. The goal of this project was to connect these companies in a way that helped both parties to save money while reducing the their environmental footprint. Solved through a user friendly database, that can easily identify the closest waste-to-resource connection.

C#, .NET MVC, MySQL, MongoDB, JavaScript, Git

Framework agreement order application, Moderniseringsstyrelsen

Software architect / developer

Nov 2015 - Jun 2016

An application for the public sector, when employees need to buy materials or book hotels under a framework agreement. First the basket is filled, then the system findes the best supplier and sends the order.

Integration for the CVR web API.

CV english.md 8/1/2018

C#, .NET MVC, JavaScript, MSSQL, HTML5 / Sass / CSS3, Foundation (CSS), Git

Launch, Public Ally

Software architect / developer / co-owner

Aug 2015 - Jun 2016

The idea behind Launch was to make public procurement easier for the public sector, by offering tools to manage and control the process and dialogue with potential suppliers, while also integrating with the Danish portal for procurements and EU's TED systems. I was a part of the group who developed the idea and the product from the bottom. The idea was good and found a lot of support, but the group lacked experience in executing an ambitious product development process. We ran out of resources, and the project became my failed startup.

Integration for TED (EU).

C#, .NET Web API, React, JavaScript, HTML5 / Sass / CSS3, Foundation (CSS)

Aggregation of revenue data, Relevant Media

Softwarearkitekt / Teknisk projektleder / Udvikler

Maj 2015 - Aug 2017

Tool for aggregating and visualizing revenue data for publishers, who present banner ads from a range of sources. Data is synchronized and massaged to fit a common data model, after which it can be effectively queried. Followed a microservice architecture.

Integrations for WideOrdbit / Admeta, Adform, Pubmatic, Rubicon, Cxense, Improve Digital, Google Ads.

Microservices, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, ES6, React, Docker, Webpack, Git

Publishing tool, Relevant Media

Software architect / developer

Nov 2014 - Aug 2017

Development of a hub for publication of ad campaigns for advertisers, across a range of ad systems.

Integrations for WideOrdbit / Admeta, Adform, Pubmatic, Rubicon, Cxense, Improve Digital, Google Ads.

Node.js, Express, MongoDB, ES6, React, Redux, Material Design, Webpack, Git

Self service platform for members, Danish Selvbetjening for medlemmer, The Association of Danish Physiotherapists

Software architect / developer

Since Dec 2014 (recurring assignments)

Self service system for registration and administration for existing members. Comprehensive data collection with complicated branching and member categories.

Integration for Navision.

CV english.md 8/1/2018

C#, .NET MVC, .NET Web API, MSSQL, Navision, ES6, React, Redux, Git

Student loan self service, Statens Administration

Software architect / developer

Nov 2013 - May 2014

Development of the public self service system for administration of personal student loans on borger.dk. The user can see status of their debt and change the rate of repayment within a set of restrictions. Complicated synchronization with the database that contain all student loans.

Integration for Nemld and borger.dk.

C#, .NET MVC, MSSQL, JavaScript, Git

Accounting system for refusions, Statens Administration

Software architect / developer

May 2013 - Jun 2014

Development of accounting system for handling public refusions within the ØSC area. Complicated data model and workflows, heavily regulated.

Udvikling af regnskabssystem til at styre offentlige refusioner i ØSC-området. Kompliceret datamodel og arbejdsgange, samt tunge beregninger og krav om præcision og sikkerhed.

Integration for NemId.

C#, .NET MVC, MSSQL, JavaScript, Git

Website, Danish Meteorological Institute (DMI)

Software architect / lead developer / teacher

2011 - 2012

New website based on TYPO3, and training of their development team for extending the functionality with TYPO3 extensions.

Integrations for internal web services (REST).

PHP, TYPO3, MySQL, JavaScript, jQuery, Git

Web-platform, VUC

Software architect / lead developer

2011 - 2012

Shared web platform for 11 VUC centers, and plugin development for educational planning and study administration.

PHP, TYPO3, MySQL, JavaScript, jQuery, Git

Website, Statens Museum for Kunst

CV_english.md 8/1/2018

Developer

2011 - 2013

Development of components for events and exhibitions for the website.

PHP, TYPO3, MySQL, JavaScript, jQuery, Git

Website, Administrationshuset

Lead developer

2011 - 2013

Development of components for administration of housing cooperatives (Danish: "andelsboligforeninger").

PHP, TYPO3, MySQL, JavaScript, jQuery, SVN

Webshop for children's clothes, Ticket to Heaven

Developer

2011

Maintenance and development of small new features in a TYPO3 based webshop.

PHP, TYPO3, MySQL, JavaScript, Ember.js, jQuery, Git

TopDanmark

Developer / on-site consultant

May 2011 - Sep 2011

Development of components for the self-service system on TopDanmarks website, in connection to a relaunch of the main website.

PHP, TYPO3, MySQL, JavaScript, jQuery, Git

Volunteer work

Pro-bono projects.

- Design and implementation of website for the author Line-Maria Lång.
- Design and implementation of website for Det Lille Risteri (English: "The small roastery").
- Modules for review and commenting on Pantbørsens website.
- Green footsteps, Roskilde Festival documentation system for reviewing "green achievements", where festival guests wanting to live in the green camp could be accepted.
- Implementation of website for Iværksætterhjælpen.
- Implementation of website for Transmogriffen.